Matthew J. Finnell

(425) 351-2896 Mattfinnell104@gmail.com https://github.com/mattfinnell

Profile

Software Development Engineer with 3 years experience, I am proficient with both backend and frontend development using C#, Python, Javascript, SQL, HTML5 and CSS3. I focus on web application development using micro service architecture and strive for code clarity and quality. I enjoy interacting and collaborating with developers, designers and team members.

Experience

SPIE - Software Engineering Intern

June 2015 - June 2016

I contributed to upgrading portions of website infrastructure from .NET V2.0 to .NET MVC V4.0. I rewrote many aspx webforms to take on a new graphical front end, be MVC compliant, and communicate between existing SQL databases and Sharepoint.

Technology Alliance Group NW - Volunteer Developer

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

I helped design a backend system that would pull in JSON and XML data from multiple APIs and perform data checks to ensure that data is consistent between each API. This was implemented with a Python backend that communicated with RESTful Web Services and a variety of databases.

Prepared Response - Front End Web Development Intern

June 2014 - Jan 2015

Collaborated with both graphic designers and developers to redesign the corporate website. I successfully reimplemented the new site using HTML5, twitter bootstrap, jQuery and AJAX. The resulting website was more dynamic, responsive and leaner than the previous website.

Education

Bellevue Senior High School Western Washington University (Computer Science)

Skills

Backend Development using Java, C#, Python and Node.js Frontend Development using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript Database Management using T-SQL, postgreSQL and mongoDB Web Service Interaction using RESTful APIs and Sharepoint Version Control using Git and TFS